<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Tech &#8211; Daily Topics</title>
	<atom:link href="https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/category/tech/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic</link>
	<description>Just another WordPress site</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2022 11:21:32 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/favicon.png</url>
	<title>Tech &#8211; Daily Topics</title>
	<link>https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>This is how the Abu Dhabi-Dubai Etihad Rails train will appear.</title>
		<link>https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/2022/01/22/this-is-how-the-abu-dhabi-dubai-etihad-rails-train-will-appear-2/</link>
					<comments>https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/2022/01/22/this-is-how-the-abu-dhabi-dubai-etihad-rails-train-will-appear-2/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2022 11:21:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/?p=300</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The first images of Etihad Rails are now available. These images depict the design and appearance of the passenger trains operated by Ethiad Rail in the United Arab Emirates. The carriages on these trains are silver and grey with a red Etihad Rail logo. These images also show the interiors, providing the first look at [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/2022/01/22/this-is-how-the-abu-dhabi-dubai-etihad-rails-train-will-appear-2/">This is how the Abu Dhabi-Dubai Etihad Rails train will appear.</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic">Daily Topics</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="has-medium-font-size">The first images of Etihad Rails are now available. These images depict the design and appearance of the passenger trains operated by Ethiad Rail in the United Arab Emirates. The carriages on these trains are silver and grey with a red Etihad Rail logo. These images also show the interiors, providing the first look at what these trains will be like on the inside.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">According to reports, these trains will connect 11 cities and areas across the UAE, from Al Sila (in the west) to Fujairah (northern part). The trains will travel at a speed of 200 kmph between these points, seating 400 people inside the carriages.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">According to Etihad Rail, the stations will be designed to celebrate regional traditions. Additionally, the idea is to build some of the stations in cities, though the location is not yet finalized. “We see the stations as urban centers where people can gather,” said Ahmed Al Hashemi, executive director of Etihad Rail passengers, in a statement.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">These trains carriages will be equipped with Wi-Fi, charging stations, entertainment systems, and food and beverages for everyone in the UAE. In addition, for convenience, the rail system will be integrated with other modes of public transportation.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">The train is expected to take fifty minutes to travel from Abu Dhabi to Dubai and around 100 minutes to travel from Abu Dhabi to Fujairah. The entire system is expected to generate Dh 23 billion in profits and provide approximately 9,000 jobs.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">Etihad Rail was founded in 2009, and the passenger rail service was announced in December of last year. However, no information about the launch has been released as of yet.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/2022/01/22/this-is-how-the-abu-dhabi-dubai-etihad-rails-train-will-appear-2/">This is how the Abu Dhabi-Dubai Etihad Rails train will appear.</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic">Daily Topics</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/2022/01/22/this-is-how-the-abu-dhabi-dubai-etihad-rails-train-will-appear-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Reliance Jio is making the most money from its subscribers than it has ever made.</title>
		<link>https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/2022/01/22/reliance-jio-is-making-the-most-money-from-its-subscribers-than-it-has-ever-made/</link>
					<comments>https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/2022/01/22/reliance-jio-is-making-the-most-money-from-its-subscribers-than-it-has-ever-made/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2022 11:09:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/?p=272</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Reliance Jio, India&#8217;s largest telecom provider, announced its Q3 FY22 results on Friday. Jio&#8217;s average revenue per user has risen above 150 in the last three months, matching the level seen exactly a year ago, before the second wave of COVID-19 hit the country. Despite this, Jio&#8217;s subscriber count fell from the previous quarter. Reliance [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/2022/01/22/reliance-jio-is-making-the-most-money-from-its-subscribers-than-it-has-ever-made/">Reliance Jio is making the most money from its subscribers than it has ever made.</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic">Daily Topics</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<ul class="has-medium-font-size"><li>Reliance Jio, India&#8217;s largest telecom provider, announced its Q3 FY22 results on Friday.</li><li>Jio&#8217;s average revenue per user has risen above 150 in the last three months, matching the level seen exactly a year ago, before the second wave of COVID-19 hit the country.</li><li>Despite this, Jio&#8217;s subscriber count fell from the previous quarter.</li></ul>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">Reliance Jio, India&#8217;s largest telecom company, announced its financial results for the period October to December 2021, revealing strong momentum in the amount it earns on average from each subscriber, also known as ARPU (average revenue per user).</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">Between October and December 2021, Reliance Jio&#8217;s earnings before interest, tax, depreciation, and amortization (EBITDA) increased by 18%, far exceeding analyst expectations of 4-5% growth.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">Surprisingly, this is Jio&#8217;s highest ARPU to date, surpassing the December 2020 figure. This is after accounting for the change in the IUC (interconnect usage charges) regime, which went into effect in January 2021 and resulted in a drop in ARPU numbers for all telecom companies.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">After ignoring analyst warnings for several months, Jio finally raised tariffs after rivals Airtel and Vodafone Idea announced 20-25 percent hikes. Jio&#8217;s tariffs remain the lowest of the three, and JP Morgan analysts expect the benefits of this increase to be realized only in the June 2022 quarter.</p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-full"><img loading="lazy" width="799" height="458" src="https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/AAT0Oer.png" alt="" class="wp-image-289"/></figure></div>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">However, the Mukesh Ambani-led telco has maintained its subscriber lead over Airtel and Vodafone Idea. The introduction of the low-cost JioPhone Next has helped the telco maintain its lead over rival Airtel.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">Jio reported a total customer base of 421 million subscribers, a decrease from the previous quarter&#8217;s figure of 430 million. However, this is still lower than the figure from the June quarter.</p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-full"><img loading="lazy" width="799" height="465" src="https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/AAT0Hsq.png" alt="" class="wp-image-288"/></figure></div>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">Last quarter&#8217;s revenue for Reliance Jio</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">Jio&#8217;s profit increased by 2% between October and December 2021, rising to 3,795 crores from 3,728 crores in the previous quarter. On a year-over-year basis, its profit increased by nearly 9%. </p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-full"><img loading="lazy" width="799" height="451" src="https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/AAT0Oey.png" alt="" class="wp-image-287"/></figure></div>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">This quarter, both data and voice usage increased significantly.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">When compared to the previous quarter, data traffic increased by nearly 6%. During the quarter, the average data usage per user was 18.4GB, up from 17.6GB the previous quarter.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">Voice usage increased to 901 minutes from 840 minutes the previous quarter.</p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-full"><img loading="lazy" width="799" height="458" src="https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/AAT0FgE.png" alt="" class="wp-image-294"/></figure></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/2022/01/22/reliance-jio-is-making-the-most-money-from-its-subscribers-than-it-has-ever-made/">Reliance Jio is making the most money from its subscribers than it has ever made.</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic">Daily Topics</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/2022/01/22/reliance-jio-is-making-the-most-money-from-its-subscribers-than-it-has-ever-made/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Mirror Deployment Process for the James Webb Space Telescope is Complete.</title>
		<link>https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/2022/01/22/the-mirror-deployment-process-for-the-james-webb-space-telescope-is-complete/</link>
					<comments>https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/2022/01/22/the-mirror-deployment-process-for-the-james-webb-space-telescope-is-complete/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2022 10:24:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/?p=278</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The largest space telescope, the James Webb Space Telescope, has used all of its hexagonal mirror segments. The delicate operation of removing the individual mirror segments of the James Webb observatory from their launch positions took nearly a week. NASA stated that its engineers sent commands to the motors, known as actuators, to slowly move [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/2022/01/22/the-mirror-deployment-process-for-the-james-webb-space-telescope-is-complete/">The Mirror Deployment Process for the James Webb Space Telescope is Complete.</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic">Daily Topics</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="has-medium-font-size">The largest space telescope, the James Webb Space Telescope, has used all of its hexagonal mirror segments. The delicate operation of removing the individual mirror segments of the James Webb observatory from their launch positions took nearly a week. NASA stated that its engineers sent commands to the motors, known as actuators, to slowly move each segment about half the length of a paper clip in order to free the mirrors from their launch restraints and provide enough space for mirror alignment.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">The James Webb space telescope will now begin its orbit around the sun. The telescope will be nearly one million miles from Earth. Erin Wolf, the mission&#8217;s program manager, also described how the mirrors on the James Webb observatory were moved and tested. He claimed that the motors had completed over a million revolutions this week. The team relocated all 132 actuators in the primary and secondary mirror segments. He explained that the actuators free the mirrors from their launch restraints and give each segment space to be adjusted later in other directions by using six motors that deploy each segment about half the length of a paper clip.</p>



<center><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Our mirror segment deployments are complete! <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f389.png" alt="🎉" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> <br><br>Using motors, each segment was moved out about half the length of a paper clip to clear the mirrors from their launch restraints and give each segment enough space for mirror alignment. <a href="https://t.co/XWbVLQuch1">https://t.co/XWbVLQuch1</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/UnfoldTheUniverse?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#UnfoldTheUniverse</a> <a href="https://t.co/d121DHldiX">pic.twitter.com/d121DHldiX</a></p>&mdash; NASA Webb Telescope (@NASAWebb) <a href="https://twitter.com/NASAWebb/status/1483944717826068484?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 19, 2022</a></blockquote> <script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></center>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">The alignment process will now take about three months. NASA will fire the James Webb telescope&#8217;s thrusters on January 24 to propel it into its orbit around the sun. The mission will be live-streamed on NASA&#8217;s Science Live website, as well as on YouTube, Facebook, and Twitter.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/2022/01/22/the-mirror-deployment-process-for-the-james-webb-space-telescope-is-complete/">The Mirror Deployment Process for the James Webb Space Telescope is Complete.</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic">Daily Topics</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/2022/01/22/the-mirror-deployment-process-for-the-james-webb-space-telescope-is-complete/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Samsung teases Unpacked 2022 event in February: What to Expect</title>
		<link>https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/2022/01/21/samsung-teases-unpacked-2022-event-in-february-what-to-expect/</link>
					<comments>https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/2022/01/21/samsung-teases-unpacked-2022-event-in-february-what-to-expect/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2022 17:44:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/?p=226</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The launch of the Samsung Galaxy S22 series is just around the corner, with the company confirming that its Unpacked 2022 event will take place in February. Samsung promises that the next generation flagships will provide a better user experience. Samsung President TM Roh hinted in a blog post that the Galaxy S series could [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/2022/01/21/samsung-teases-unpacked-2022-event-in-february-what-to-expect/">Samsung teases Unpacked 2022 event in February: What to Expect</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic">Daily Topics</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="has-text-align-left has-medium-font-size">The launch of the Samsung Galaxy S22 series is just around the corner, with the company confirming that its Unpacked 2022 event will take place in February. Samsung promises that the next generation flagships will provide a better user experience. Samsung President TM Roh hinted in a blog post that the Galaxy S series could include a Note-series-like device as well. It is also expected to unveil its new Galaxy Tab S8 tablets at the event. Here&#8217;s a rundown of everything Samsung is expected to reveal next month.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size"><strong>The date of the Samsung Galaxy Unpacked 2022 event has been leaked.</strong></p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">While the company has yet to confirm the event date, Ice Universe, a well-known leaker, claimed on Weibo that Samsung will hold its Galaxy Unpacked 2022 event on February 9. However, according to a report in the Korean publication DDaily, the event could begin on February 8. According to reports, the event will begin at 23:00 PM CST, which is 8:30 PM in India.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size"><strong>What can we expect from the Samsung Unpacked 2022 event?</strong></p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">The Samsung Galaxy S22 Ultra is widely rumored to be the new Samsung Galaxy Note series phone this year, something that the company&#8217;s President has also hinted at. The terms &#8220;notable S series&#8221; and &#8220;the next evolution of Galaxy&#8221; both refer to the same thing. The company has also posted a short video on YouTube, implying that the brand intends to offer a mix of Galaxy S and Note series, which the Galaxy S22 Ultra may offer.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">&#8220;At Unpacked in February 2022, we&#8217;ll unveil the most notable S series device we&#8217;ve ever created.&#8221; &#8220;The next generation of Galaxy S is here, combining the best of our Samsung Galaxy into one ultimate device,&#8221; he wrote.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">&#8220;We understand that many of you were disappointed when Samsung did not release a new Galaxy Note last year. You adored the Galaxy Note series&#8217; unrivaled creativity and efficiency, which allowed you to transition from gaming nirvana to high-octane productivity in the blink of an eye. You gushed about the lifelike S Pen, which many compare to writing with ink on paper. And we haven&#8217;t forgotten about the things you enjoy,&#8221; he added.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">Samsung is expected to release three smartphones this year, including the Galaxy S22, Galaxy S22 Plus, and Galaxy S22 Ultra. The top-tier Ultra model is said to have a unique design. It may resemble Samsung&#8217;s Galaxy Note phablets and include an S-Pen slot. According to previous rumors and leaks, this one will also have a curved display, similar to the Galaxy Note 20. The Galaxy S22 Ultra may have a large 6.81-inch screen. A 5,000mAh battery and a 108-megapixel quad-camera setup were also visible. A 12-megapixel ultra-wide camera, a 10-megapixel 10x telephoto camera, and a 10-megapixel 3x telephoto camera are said to be included.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">In some countries, all three Samsung Galaxy S22 smartphones will most likely be powered by the Snapdragon 8 Gen 1 chipset. In India, the company could release devices with its new Exynos 2200 SoC and AMD graphics.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">The Galaxy S22 and its Plus variant are also expected to get camera upgrades, such as a beefier primary camera and improved optical zoom. Both handsets are expected to keep the old design and include a 50MP GN5 primary camera on the back. The standard model is expected to have a 6.01-inch screen, while the Plus is expected to have a 6.55-inch display.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">Roland Quandt, a tipster, recently suggested that the company&#8217;s 2022 flagship could finally offer faster-charging speeds. The Samsung Galaxy S22 Ultra model is expected to support 45W charging. However, because Samsung does not include a charger in the box of its flagship phones, the charging brick may have to be purchased separately. Furthermore, the other two models are said to have only 25W fast charging, which is similar to older models.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">The Samsung Galaxy Tab S8 series, in addition to the Galaxy S22 series, is expected to make its debut at the upcoming Unpacked 2022 event. While few details are known about the tablet&#8217;s specifications, it is expected to be powered by a Snapdragon 888 or Snapdragon 8 Gen 1 chipset. Three models could be unveiled by the company. The standard model is expected to have an 11.6-inch screen, while the Plus model may have a 12-inch screen. The Galaxy Tab S8 Ultra could have a massive 14.6-inch screen when it launches.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/2022/01/21/samsung-teases-unpacked-2022-event-in-february-what-to-expect/">Samsung teases Unpacked 2022 event in February: What to Expect</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic">Daily Topics</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/2022/01/21/samsung-teases-unpacked-2022-event-in-february-what-to-expect/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Oppo wants to create devices that run on mobile and Wi-Fi signals rather than batteries.</title>
		<link>https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/2022/01/21/oppo-wants-to-create-devices-that-run-on-mobile-and-wi-fi-signals-rather-than-batteries/</link>
					<comments>https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/2022/01/21/oppo-wants-to-create-devices-that-run-on-mobile-and-wi-fi-signals-rather-than-batteries/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2022 17:43:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/?p=222</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Whether it&#8217;s a mobile phone, a laptop, a tablet, or earbuds, nearly every personal gadget today is powered by a battery. However, Oppo, one of the world&#8217;s largest technology companies, believes that batteries are not the future, at least for IoT devices such as wireless earphones. It has now outlined a vision in which such [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/2022/01/21/oppo-wants-to-create-devices-that-run-on-mobile-and-wi-fi-signals-rather-than-batteries/">Oppo wants to create devices that run on mobile and Wi-Fi signals rather than batteries.</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic">Daily Topics</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="has-medium-font-size">Whether it&#8217;s a mobile phone, a laptop, a tablet, or earbuds, nearly every personal gadget today is powered by a battery. However, Oppo, one of the world&#8217;s largest technology companies, believes that batteries are not the future, at least for IoT devices such as wireless earphones. It has now outlined a vision in which such devices will be powered by mobile signals, Wi-Fi, and Bluetooth rather than batteries, which could change the way we use these products. Oppo has released a research paper titled &#8220;Zero Power Consumption Communication,&#8221; which focuses on a system that includes devices that consume no power.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">Although it is only a theory at this point, the zero power consumption communication system will not use batteries for power and will instead rely on waves for charging. These devices will be ultra-portable and require much less power to operate, and with a battery-free mechanism, they will be longer-lasting and less expensive than current technology.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">Batteries are an essential component of any personal electronic device that people carry with them. In contrast to the direct power supply system found on large appliances such as televisions and refrigerators, batteries enable devices to be portable. However, the way batteries work has several limitations.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">The first and most important limitation is that they are consumable, which means they will become less effective and lose capacity as they age. Second, they take up a lot of room. If you&#8217;ve ever looked inside a smartphone, you&#8217;ll notice that the battery takes up the most space. They are also quite heavy. Given that they both use the same build material, a phone with a 6000mAh battery will most likely weigh more than a phone with a 4000mAh battery. Third, batteries are costly and add to the overall cost of your phone. Fourth, batteries are vulnerable to damage and explosions if the environment in which they operate changes slightly. You&#8217;ve probably heard about phones exploding. Finally, batteries are harmful to the environment.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">Oppo wants to change everything. It has proposed technology for collecting radiofrequency energy from wireless connections such as mobile networks, Wi-Fi, and Bluetooth, which originate from RF sources such as TV towers, FM towers, mobile network base stations, and Wi-Fi hotspots. By modulating and relaying incoming signals, they will be able to communicate.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">What Oppo has envisioned appears efficient and promising, and if implemented, could improve the ease with which we use some gadgets. However, it will mostly be limited to devices with low energy requirements, so it is difficult to imagine zero power consumption communication technology being able to power devices such as smartphones.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/2022/01/21/oppo-wants-to-create-devices-that-run-on-mobile-and-wi-fi-signals-rather-than-batteries/">Oppo wants to create devices that run on mobile and Wi-Fi signals rather than batteries.</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic">Daily Topics</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/2022/01/21/oppo-wants-to-create-devices-that-run-on-mobile-and-wi-fi-signals-rather-than-batteries/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Radian Aerospace has raised $27.5 million to build the world&#8217;s first spaceplane.</title>
		<link>https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/2022/01/21/radian-aerospace-has-raised-27-5-million-to-build-the-worlds-first-space-plane/</link>
					<comments>https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/2022/01/21/radian-aerospace-has-raised-27-5-million-to-build-the-worlds-first-space-plane/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2022 17:43:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/?p=228</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Radian Aerospace is working on a spaceplane that can transport people and light cargo to low-Earth orbit. The space plane will be fully reusable and capable of returning to Earth within 48 hours of landing. It will also be able to deliver up to 2,270 kgs anywhere in the world in under an hour. More [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/2022/01/21/radian-aerospace-has-raised-27-5-million-to-build-the-worlds-first-space-plane/">Radian Aerospace has raised $27.5 million to build the world&#8217;s first spaceplane.</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic">Daily Topics</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<ul class="has-medium-font-size"><li>Radian Aerospace is working on a spaceplane that can transport people and light cargo to low-Earth orbit.</li></ul>



<ul class="has-medium-font-size"><li>The space plane will be fully reusable and capable of returning to Earth within 48 hours of landing.</li></ul>



<ul class="has-medium-font-size"><li>It will also be able to deliver up to 2,270 kgs anywhere in the world in under an hour.</li></ul>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">More people are flying to and from space, making space travel more accessible. There are advancements in various space travel means, such as a hot air balloon that will allow you to travel to the stratosphere. Another option for space travel is to use a plane that can transport both people and payloads.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">Radian Aerospace, based in Washington, is developing a spaceplane called &#8216;Radian One,&#8217; which recently received $27.5 million in seed funding. Radian One, the &#8220;world&#8217;s first fully functional horizontal takeoff and landing, single-stage to orbit vehicle,&#8221; will be developed with the funds.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">So far, the company has been operating in stealth mode, focusing on the design and early development of the space plane, and the new investment will propel it forward.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size"><strong>The spaceplane Radian One</strong></p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">Radian One will be shaped and designed like a plane, which means it will have wings, which will make a significant difference in spaceflight. As a result, it will carry out aircraft-like operations, delivering people and light cargo to low-Earth orbit (LEO). In contrast to current vertical liftoffs, the space plane will launch and land horizontally. However, the space plane will require some assistance during takeoff, which will be provided by a sled.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">Radian One will be able to perform a mission, refuel, and fly again 48 hours after touchdown, in addition to flying to space. The spacecraft is designed to be fully reusable, with the ability to stay in orbit for five days.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">According to space.com, the Radian One is also designed to fly here on Earth, with the ability to deliver up to 2,270 kgs anywhere in the world in less than an hour.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">According to the company, its focus is not on space tourism, but on making space travel more convenient. &#8220;We are not focused on tourism; we are dedicated to missions that improve life on our own planet, such as research, in-space manufacturing, and terrestrial observation, as well as critical new missions such as rapid global delivery right here on Earth,&#8221; said Richard Humphrey, Radian&#8217;s CEO, and co-founder.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">Radian&#8217;s solution is said to be a low-cost space transportation system that can aid in the development of new aerospace markets. However, no launch date for the Radian One has been revealed as of yet, but the ambitious space plane is worth the wait.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/2022/01/21/radian-aerospace-has-raised-27-5-million-to-build-the-worlds-first-space-plane/">Radian Aerospace has raised $27.5 million to build the world&#8217;s first spaceplane.</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic">Daily Topics</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/2022/01/21/radian-aerospace-has-raised-27-5-million-to-build-the-worlds-first-space-plane/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Xiaomi 11T Pro has been launched in India and will be available for purchase on Amazon Great Republic Day 2022.</title>
		<link>https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/2022/01/20/xiaomi-11t-pro-has-been-launched-in-india-and-will-be-available-for-purchase-on-amazon-great-republic-day-2022/</link>
					<comments>https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/2022/01/20/xiaomi-11t-pro-has-been-launched-in-india-and-will-be-available-for-purchase-on-amazon-great-republic-day-2022/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2022 07:27:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/?p=188</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The price and availability of the Xiaomi 11T Pro in India have been announced. The device is Xiaomi&#8217;s new premium smartphone in India, competing with the OnePlus 9RT. The Xiaomi 11T Pro will be available for purchase beginning at 2 p.m. on January 19 as part of Amazon&#8217;s Great Republic Day Sale. There are three [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/2022/01/20/xiaomi-11t-pro-has-been-launched-in-india-and-will-be-available-for-purchase-on-amazon-great-republic-day-2022/">Xiaomi 11T Pro has been launched in India and will be available for purchase on Amazon Great Republic Day 2022.</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic">Daily Topics</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="has-medium-font-size">The price and availability of the Xiaomi 11T Pro in India have been announced. The device is Xiaomi&#8217;s new premium smartphone in India, competing with the OnePlus 9RT. The Xiaomi 11T Pro will be available for purchase beginning at 2 p.m. on January 19 as part of Amazon&#8217;s Great Republic Day Sale.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">There are three storage options for the Xiaomi 11T Pro. The phone&#8217;s base model has 8GB of RAM and 128GB of storage. The price is Rs 39,999. There is also an 8GB+ 256GB variant available for Rs 41,999. Finally, the top-tier 12GB + 256GB variant costs Rs 43,999. The phone is available in three colors: Meteorite Black, Moonlight White, and Celestial Magic.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">Customers with a CITI Bank card can get a Rs 5000 discount on the Xiaomi 11T Pro during the sale as part of the launch offers.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">The Xiaomi 11T Pro undercuts its archrival, the OnePlus 9RT, in terms of pricing (hands-on review). OnePlus released the 9RT with two storage options. The OnePlus 9RT price in India is Rs 42,999 for the 8GB + 128GB variant, and Rs 46,999 for the 12GB + 256GB variant.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">The Xiaomi 11T Pro will be available for purchase on Amazon India, Mi Home Stores, and Mi.com beginning at 2 p.m. on January 19.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size"><strong>Specifications for the Xiaomi 11T Pro</strong></p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">The display on the Xiaomi 11T Pro is 6.67-inch Full HD+ AMOLED with a 20:9 aspect ratio. The phone has a flat-screen with a hole-punch cutout in the top center for the front-facing 16MP camera. The screen has a peak brightness of 1000 nits and is HD10+ certified.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">The phone is powered by a Qualcomm Snapdragon 888 SoC. It has 256GB of storage and up to 12GB of RAM. The Xiaomi 11T Pro comes with a 5,000 mAh battery that supports 120W Xiaomi HyperCharge fast charging. According to the manufacturer, the phone can be fully charged in 17 minutes. We&#8217;ll put the claim to the test in our upcoming Xiaomi 11T Pro review.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">The Xiaomi 11T Pro camera module has a triple-sensor setup on the back. The primary sensor is a 108MP Samsung ISOCELL HM2 sensor, which is also found in the Xiaomi 11i HyperCharge (Review). The main camera lacks optical image stabilization (OIS), but Xiaomi claims that the camera on the 11T Pro captures more frames at multiple exposures and merges them to process the final output.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">In addition, the device has an 8MP ultrawide camera and a 5MP tele-macro camera. In terms of software, the Xiaomi smartphone comes pre-installed with Android 11-based MIUI 12.5. It has dual speakers tuned by Harmon Kardon with Dolby Atmos, which is also available on the flagship Mi 11 Ultra (Review)</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/2022/01/20/xiaomi-11t-pro-has-been-launched-in-india-and-will-be-available-for-purchase-on-amazon-great-republic-day-2022/">Xiaomi 11T Pro has been launched in India and will be available for purchase on Amazon Great Republic Day 2022.</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic">Daily Topics</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/2022/01/20/xiaomi-11t-pro-has-been-launched-in-india-and-will-be-available-for-purchase-on-amazon-great-republic-day-2022/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>In India, Kodak introduces Magsafe wireless iPhone chargers for the car and home.</title>
		<link>https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/2022/01/20/in-india-kodak-introduces-magsafe-wireless-iphone-chargers-for-the-car-and-home/</link>
					<comments>https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/2022/01/20/in-india-kodak-introduces-magsafe-wireless-iphone-chargers-for-the-car-and-home/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2022 07:25:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[World]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/?p=187</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Kodak, a well-known photography company based in the United States, is collaborating with an Indian company, Georgian Enterprises, to launch wireless chargers for the Apple iPhone 12 and iPhone 13 series in India. The price of the two wireless chargers, the Kodak car WCM101C, is Rs 2,499. &#8220;We are excited to announce this licensing agreement [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/2022/01/20/in-india-kodak-introduces-magsafe-wireless-iphone-chargers-for-the-car-and-home/">In India, Kodak introduces Magsafe wireless iPhone chargers for the car and home.</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic">Daily Topics</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="has-medium-font-size">Kodak, a well-known photography company based in the United States, is collaborating with an Indian company, Georgian Enterprises, to launch wireless chargers for the Apple iPhone 12 and iPhone 13 series in India. The price of the two wireless chargers, the Kodak car WCM101C, is Rs 2,499.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">&#8220;We are excited to announce this licensing agreement with Georgian Enterprises to further expand Kodak&#8217;s consumer electronics presence in the Indian market,&#8221; said Clara Fort, Vice President of Global Brand Licensing for Kodak.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">Kodak, a well-known photography company based in the United States, is collaborating with an Indian company, Georgian Enterprises, to launch wireless chargers for the Apple iPhone 12 and iPhone 13 series in India. The price of the two wireless chargers, the Kodak car WCM101C, is Rs 2,499.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">&#8220;We are excited to announce this licensing agreement with Georgian Enterprises to further expand Kodak&#8217;s consumer electronics presence in the Indian market,&#8221; said Clara Fort, Vice President of Global Brand Licensing for Kodak.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">The charger&#8217;s body also features a 360-degree rotating ball mount that allows you to position your iPhone horizontally or vertically. When using your phone for navigation, this helps to create a suitable and optimal viewing angle with the best display position.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">The Kodak Magnetic Wireless Charger WCM201 for home or office also includes a high-speed 15W desk chargercum-stand. It has the same neodymium magnets for a secure hold as the car charger, but it has a compact kickstand that allows users to position the phone upright.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">Both the Kodak Magnetic Wireless Charger for Car and the Kodak Magnetic Wireless Charger for Home is compatible with Apple&#8217;s iPhone 13, iPhone 13 Pro, and iPhone 13 Pro Max. iPhone 13 Mini, iPhone 12 Pro, iPhone 12 Pro Max, and iPhone 12 Mini.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">All you need is a compatible USB car or wall charger with a power output of up to 20 watts for maximum charging speed. The chargers come with a USB cable and a one-year standard warranty.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/2022/01/20/in-india-kodak-introduces-magsafe-wireless-iphone-chargers-for-the-car-and-home/">In India, Kodak introduces Magsafe wireless iPhone chargers for the car and home.</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic">Daily Topics</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/2022/01/20/in-india-kodak-introduces-magsafe-wireless-iphone-chargers-for-the-car-and-home/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Hands-free but precise is mixed reality.</title>
		<link>https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/2022/01/20/hands-free-but-precise-is-mixed-reality/</link>
					<comments>https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/2022/01/20/hands-free-but-precise-is-mixed-reality/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2022 05:05:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/?p=161</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>We &#8220;We are in a new era of computing, in which the digital world expands beyond two-dimensional screens and enters &#8220;We are in a new era of computing, in which the digital world expands two-dimensional screens and enters the three-dimensional world,&#8221; said Rajiv Sodhi, chief operating officer of Microsoft India. &#8220;HoloLens 2 enables businesses and [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/2022/01/20/hands-free-but-precise-is-mixed-reality/">Hands-free but precise is mixed reality.</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic">Daily Topics</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="has-medium-font-size">We &#8220;We are in a new era of computing, in which the digital world expands beyond two-dimensional screens and enters &#8220;We are in a new era of computing, in which the digital world expands two-dimensional screens and enters the three-dimensional world,&#8221; said Rajiv Sodhi, chief operating officer of Microsoft India. &#8220;HoloLens 2 enables businesses and their employees to complete critical tasks faster, safer, and more efficiently, while also creating new ways to connect with customers and partners.&#8221; Microsoft India recently announced that the HoloLens 2 is now available in the country, bringing the capabilities and value of mixed reality solutions to Indian enterprises across industries.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">For those who are unfamiliar, the HoloLens2 is an ergonomic, untethered self-contained holographic device with enterprise-ready applications to improve user accuracy and output. Mixed reality combines the physical and digital worlds, ranging from augmented reality to virtual reality. This augments the jobs of front-line workers in industries such as manufacturing, automotive, healthcare, and education, resulting in significant benefits for these businesses and industries.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">According to a recent Forrester Total Economic Impact Study commissioned by Microsoft, it provided a 177 percent return on investment over three years, as well as improvements in employee health and safety, business continuity, customer experience, and customer outcomes.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">Apollo Hospitals has developed an AI-powered Cardiovascular Disease Risk Score API that predicts an individual&#8217;s risk of having a cardiac event within the next seven years. Using the immersive mixed reality experience of the HoloLens 2, this API is combined with an individual&#8217;s health vitals to create a 3D visualization of the person&#8217;s heart&#8217;s current and future states. &#8220;By providing this immersive mixed reality experience and explaining the cause and effect of one&#8217;s lifestyle, the conversation between the doctor and patient has become much more personalized and impactful,&#8221; said Sathya Sriram, CEO of Apollo Hospitals Preventive Health.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/2022/01/20/hands-free-but-precise-is-mixed-reality/">Hands-free but precise is mixed reality.</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic">Daily Topics</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/2022/01/20/hands-free-but-precise-is-mixed-reality/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Apple iPhone SE+ 5G to be released in 2022; 5.7-inch display expected in next model</title>
		<link>https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/2022/01/18/apple-iphone-se-5g-to-be-released-in-2022-5-7-inch-display-expected-in-next-model-2/</link>
					<comments>https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/2022/01/18/apple-iphone-se-5g-to-be-released-in-2022-5-7-inch-display-expected-in-next-model-2/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2022 11:48:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/?p=134</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Apple will release the new iPhone SE in a few months, and this model is expected to resemble the older iPhone SE smartphones. Display Supply Chain Consultants CEO Ross Young has also stated that the iPhone SE that will be released this year will be known as the iPhone SE+ 5G. As the name suggests, [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/2022/01/18/apple-iphone-se-5g-to-be-released-in-2022-5-7-inch-display-expected-in-next-model-2/">Apple iPhone SE+ 5G to be released in 2022; 5.7-inch display expected in next model</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic">Daily Topics</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="has-medium-font-size">Apple will release the new iPhone SE in a few months, and this model is expected to resemble the older iPhone SE smartphones. Display Supply Chain Consultants CEO Ross Young has also stated that the iPhone SE that will be released this year will be known as the iPhone SE+ 5G.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">As the name suggests, this smartphone will have 5G support and is expected to use the same 4.7-inch LCD panel as Apple&#8217;s previous 2020 iPhone SE, as well as the same design.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">According to other reports, the iPhone SE+ 5G will have a single camera on the back with an LED flash. According to David Kowalski of Tentechreview.com, the 2022 iPhone SE could have a 5.69-inch screen. This information contradicts what Ross says about the screen size on the 2022 iPhone SE, so it remains to be seen which direction Apple will take with its affordable, compact iPhone SE series this year.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">According to Kowalski&#8217;s renders, Apple may forego the &#8220;massive forehead, chin, and ID button,&#8221; and the device may resemble the iPhone XR with its symmetrical bezels and notch.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">According to the renders, the power button and SIM tray will be on the right, while the volume buttons and silent mode switch will be on the left. The speaker grills will be located on either side of the lightning port at the bottom.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">The iPhone SE+ 5G is expected to be released by Apple in March or April of this year.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/2022/01/18/apple-iphone-se-5g-to-be-released-in-2022-5-7-inch-display-expected-in-next-model-2/">Apple iPhone SE+ 5G to be released in 2022; 5.7-inch display expected in next model</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic">Daily Topics</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/2022/01/18/apple-iphone-se-5g-to-be-released-in-2022-5-7-inch-display-expected-in-next-model-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
