<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Science &#8211; Daily Topics</title>
	<atom:link href="https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/category/science/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic</link>
	<description>Just another WordPress site</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2022 11:21:32 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/favicon.png</url>
	<title>Science &#8211; Daily Topics</title>
	<link>https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>This is how the Abu Dhabi-Dubai Etihad Rails train will appear.</title>
		<link>https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/2022/01/22/this-is-how-the-abu-dhabi-dubai-etihad-rails-train-will-appear-2/</link>
					<comments>https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/2022/01/22/this-is-how-the-abu-dhabi-dubai-etihad-rails-train-will-appear-2/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2022 11:21:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/?p=300</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The first images of Etihad Rails are now available. These images depict the design and appearance of the passenger trains operated by Ethiad Rail in the United Arab Emirates. The carriages on these trains are silver and grey with a red Etihad Rail logo. These images also show the interiors, providing the first look at [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/2022/01/22/this-is-how-the-abu-dhabi-dubai-etihad-rails-train-will-appear-2/">This is how the Abu Dhabi-Dubai Etihad Rails train will appear.</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic">Daily Topics</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="has-medium-font-size">The first images of Etihad Rails are now available. These images depict the design and appearance of the passenger trains operated by Ethiad Rail in the United Arab Emirates. The carriages on these trains are silver and grey with a red Etihad Rail logo. These images also show the interiors, providing the first look at what these trains will be like on the inside.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">According to reports, these trains will connect 11 cities and areas across the UAE, from Al Sila (in the west) to Fujairah (northern part). The trains will travel at a speed of 200 kmph between these points, seating 400 people inside the carriages.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">According to Etihad Rail, the stations will be designed to celebrate regional traditions. Additionally, the idea is to build some of the stations in cities, though the location is not yet finalized. “We see the stations as urban centers where people can gather,” said Ahmed Al Hashemi, executive director of Etihad Rail passengers, in a statement.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">These trains carriages will be equipped with Wi-Fi, charging stations, entertainment systems, and food and beverages for everyone in the UAE. In addition, for convenience, the rail system will be integrated with other modes of public transportation.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">The train is expected to take fifty minutes to travel from Abu Dhabi to Dubai and around 100 minutes to travel from Abu Dhabi to Fujairah. The entire system is expected to generate Dh 23 billion in profits and provide approximately 9,000 jobs.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">Etihad Rail was founded in 2009, and the passenger rail service was announced in December of last year. However, no information about the launch has been released as of yet.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/2022/01/22/this-is-how-the-abu-dhabi-dubai-etihad-rails-train-will-appear-2/">This is how the Abu Dhabi-Dubai Etihad Rails train will appear.</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic">Daily Topics</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/2022/01/22/this-is-how-the-abu-dhabi-dubai-etihad-rails-train-will-appear-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Mirror Deployment Process for the James Webb Space Telescope is Complete.</title>
		<link>https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/2022/01/22/the-mirror-deployment-process-for-the-james-webb-space-telescope-is-complete/</link>
					<comments>https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/2022/01/22/the-mirror-deployment-process-for-the-james-webb-space-telescope-is-complete/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2022 10:24:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/?p=278</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The largest space telescope, the James Webb Space Telescope, has used all of its hexagonal mirror segments. The delicate operation of removing the individual mirror segments of the James Webb observatory from their launch positions took nearly a week. NASA stated that its engineers sent commands to the motors, known as actuators, to slowly move [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/2022/01/22/the-mirror-deployment-process-for-the-james-webb-space-telescope-is-complete/">The Mirror Deployment Process for the James Webb Space Telescope is Complete.</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic">Daily Topics</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="has-medium-font-size">The largest space telescope, the James Webb Space Telescope, has used all of its hexagonal mirror segments. The delicate operation of removing the individual mirror segments of the James Webb observatory from their launch positions took nearly a week. NASA stated that its engineers sent commands to the motors, known as actuators, to slowly move each segment about half the length of a paper clip in order to free the mirrors from their launch restraints and provide enough space for mirror alignment.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">The James Webb space telescope will now begin its orbit around the sun. The telescope will be nearly one million miles from Earth. Erin Wolf, the mission&#8217;s program manager, also described how the mirrors on the James Webb observatory were moved and tested. He claimed that the motors had completed over a million revolutions this week. The team relocated all 132 actuators in the primary and secondary mirror segments. He explained that the actuators free the mirrors from their launch restraints and give each segment space to be adjusted later in other directions by using six motors that deploy each segment about half the length of a paper clip.</p>



<center><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Our mirror segment deployments are complete! <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f389.png" alt="🎉" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> <br><br>Using motors, each segment was moved out about half the length of a paper clip to clear the mirrors from their launch restraints and give each segment enough space for mirror alignment. <a href="https://t.co/XWbVLQuch1">https://t.co/XWbVLQuch1</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/UnfoldTheUniverse?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#UnfoldTheUniverse</a> <a href="https://t.co/d121DHldiX">pic.twitter.com/d121DHldiX</a></p>&mdash; NASA Webb Telescope (@NASAWebb) <a href="https://twitter.com/NASAWebb/status/1483944717826068484?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 19, 2022</a></blockquote> <script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></center>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">The alignment process will now take about three months. NASA will fire the James Webb telescope&#8217;s thrusters on January 24 to propel it into its orbit around the sun. The mission will be live-streamed on NASA&#8217;s Science Live website, as well as on YouTube, Facebook, and Twitter.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/2022/01/22/the-mirror-deployment-process-for-the-james-webb-space-telescope-is-complete/">The Mirror Deployment Process for the James Webb Space Telescope is Complete.</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic">Daily Topics</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/2022/01/22/the-mirror-deployment-process-for-the-james-webb-space-telescope-is-complete/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Radian Aerospace has raised $27.5 million to build the world&#8217;s first spaceplane.</title>
		<link>https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/2022/01/21/radian-aerospace-has-raised-27-5-million-to-build-the-worlds-first-space-plane/</link>
					<comments>https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/2022/01/21/radian-aerospace-has-raised-27-5-million-to-build-the-worlds-first-space-plane/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2022 17:43:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/?p=228</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Radian Aerospace is working on a spaceplane that can transport people and light cargo to low-Earth orbit. The space plane will be fully reusable and capable of returning to Earth within 48 hours of landing. It will also be able to deliver up to 2,270 kgs anywhere in the world in under an hour. More [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/2022/01/21/radian-aerospace-has-raised-27-5-million-to-build-the-worlds-first-space-plane/">Radian Aerospace has raised $27.5 million to build the world&#8217;s first spaceplane.</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic">Daily Topics</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<ul class="has-medium-font-size"><li>Radian Aerospace is working on a spaceplane that can transport people and light cargo to low-Earth orbit.</li></ul>



<ul class="has-medium-font-size"><li>The space plane will be fully reusable and capable of returning to Earth within 48 hours of landing.</li></ul>



<ul class="has-medium-font-size"><li>It will also be able to deliver up to 2,270 kgs anywhere in the world in under an hour.</li></ul>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">More people are flying to and from space, making space travel more accessible. There are advancements in various space travel means, such as a hot air balloon that will allow you to travel to the stratosphere. Another option for space travel is to use a plane that can transport both people and payloads.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">Radian Aerospace, based in Washington, is developing a spaceplane called &#8216;Radian One,&#8217; which recently received $27.5 million in seed funding. Radian One, the &#8220;world&#8217;s first fully functional horizontal takeoff and landing, single-stage to orbit vehicle,&#8221; will be developed with the funds.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">So far, the company has been operating in stealth mode, focusing on the design and early development of the space plane, and the new investment will propel it forward.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size"><strong>The spaceplane Radian One</strong></p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">Radian One will be shaped and designed like a plane, which means it will have wings, which will make a significant difference in spaceflight. As a result, it will carry out aircraft-like operations, delivering people and light cargo to low-Earth orbit (LEO). In contrast to current vertical liftoffs, the space plane will launch and land horizontally. However, the space plane will require some assistance during takeoff, which will be provided by a sled.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">Radian One will be able to perform a mission, refuel, and fly again 48 hours after touchdown, in addition to flying to space. The spacecraft is designed to be fully reusable, with the ability to stay in orbit for five days.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">According to space.com, the Radian One is also designed to fly here on Earth, with the ability to deliver up to 2,270 kgs anywhere in the world in less than an hour.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">According to the company, its focus is not on space tourism, but on making space travel more convenient. &#8220;We are not focused on tourism; we are dedicated to missions that improve life on our own planet, such as research, in-space manufacturing, and terrestrial observation, as well as critical new missions such as rapid global delivery right here on Earth,&#8221; said Richard Humphrey, Radian&#8217;s CEO, and co-founder.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">Radian&#8217;s solution is said to be a low-cost space transportation system that can aid in the development of new aerospace markets. However, no launch date for the Radian One has been revealed as of yet, but the ambitious space plane is worth the wait.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/2022/01/21/radian-aerospace-has-raised-27-5-million-to-build-the-worlds-first-space-plane/">Radian Aerospace has raised $27.5 million to build the world&#8217;s first spaceplane.</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic">Daily Topics</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/2022/01/21/radian-aerospace-has-raised-27-5-million-to-build-the-worlds-first-space-plane/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>In India, Kodak introduces Magsafe wireless iPhone chargers for the car and home.</title>
		<link>https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/2022/01/20/in-india-kodak-introduces-magsafe-wireless-iphone-chargers-for-the-car-and-home/</link>
					<comments>https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/2022/01/20/in-india-kodak-introduces-magsafe-wireless-iphone-chargers-for-the-car-and-home/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2022 07:25:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[World]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/?p=187</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Kodak, a well-known photography company based in the United States, is collaborating with an Indian company, Georgian Enterprises, to launch wireless chargers for the Apple iPhone 12 and iPhone 13 series in India. The price of the two wireless chargers, the Kodak car WCM101C, is Rs 2,499. &#8220;We are excited to announce this licensing agreement [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/2022/01/20/in-india-kodak-introduces-magsafe-wireless-iphone-chargers-for-the-car-and-home/">In India, Kodak introduces Magsafe wireless iPhone chargers for the car and home.</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic">Daily Topics</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="has-medium-font-size">Kodak, a well-known photography company based in the United States, is collaborating with an Indian company, Georgian Enterprises, to launch wireless chargers for the Apple iPhone 12 and iPhone 13 series in India. The price of the two wireless chargers, the Kodak car WCM101C, is Rs 2,499.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">&#8220;We are excited to announce this licensing agreement with Georgian Enterprises to further expand Kodak&#8217;s consumer electronics presence in the Indian market,&#8221; said Clara Fort, Vice President of Global Brand Licensing for Kodak.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">Kodak, a well-known photography company based in the United States, is collaborating with an Indian company, Georgian Enterprises, to launch wireless chargers for the Apple iPhone 12 and iPhone 13 series in India. The price of the two wireless chargers, the Kodak car WCM101C, is Rs 2,499.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">&#8220;We are excited to announce this licensing agreement with Georgian Enterprises to further expand Kodak&#8217;s consumer electronics presence in the Indian market,&#8221; said Clara Fort, Vice President of Global Brand Licensing for Kodak.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">The charger&#8217;s body also features a 360-degree rotating ball mount that allows you to position your iPhone horizontally or vertically. When using your phone for navigation, this helps to create a suitable and optimal viewing angle with the best display position.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">The Kodak Magnetic Wireless Charger WCM201 for home or office also includes a high-speed 15W desk chargercum-stand. It has the same neodymium magnets for a secure hold as the car charger, but it has a compact kickstand that allows users to position the phone upright.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">Both the Kodak Magnetic Wireless Charger for Car and the Kodak Magnetic Wireless Charger for Home is compatible with Apple&#8217;s iPhone 13, iPhone 13 Pro, and iPhone 13 Pro Max. iPhone 13 Mini, iPhone 12 Pro, iPhone 12 Pro Max, and iPhone 12 Mini.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">All you need is a compatible USB car or wall charger with a power output of up to 20 watts for maximum charging speed. The chargers come with a USB cable and a one-year standard warranty.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/2022/01/20/in-india-kodak-introduces-magsafe-wireless-iphone-chargers-for-the-car-and-home/">In India, Kodak introduces Magsafe wireless iPhone chargers for the car and home.</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic">Daily Topics</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/2022/01/20/in-india-kodak-introduces-magsafe-wireless-iphone-chargers-for-the-car-and-home/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Hands-free but precise is mixed reality.</title>
		<link>https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/2022/01/20/hands-free-but-precise-is-mixed-reality/</link>
					<comments>https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/2022/01/20/hands-free-but-precise-is-mixed-reality/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2022 05:05:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/?p=161</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>We &#8220;We are in a new era of computing, in which the digital world expands beyond two-dimensional screens and enters &#8220;We are in a new era of computing, in which the digital world expands two-dimensional screens and enters the three-dimensional world,&#8221; said Rajiv Sodhi, chief operating officer of Microsoft India. &#8220;HoloLens 2 enables businesses and [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/2022/01/20/hands-free-but-precise-is-mixed-reality/">Hands-free but precise is mixed reality.</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic">Daily Topics</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="has-medium-font-size">We &#8220;We are in a new era of computing, in which the digital world expands beyond two-dimensional screens and enters &#8220;We are in a new era of computing, in which the digital world expands two-dimensional screens and enters the three-dimensional world,&#8221; said Rajiv Sodhi, chief operating officer of Microsoft India. &#8220;HoloLens 2 enables businesses and their employees to complete critical tasks faster, safer, and more efficiently, while also creating new ways to connect with customers and partners.&#8221; Microsoft India recently announced that the HoloLens 2 is now available in the country, bringing the capabilities and value of mixed reality solutions to Indian enterprises across industries.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">For those who are unfamiliar, the HoloLens2 is an ergonomic, untethered self-contained holographic device with enterprise-ready applications to improve user accuracy and output. Mixed reality combines the physical and digital worlds, ranging from augmented reality to virtual reality. This augments the jobs of front-line workers in industries such as manufacturing, automotive, healthcare, and education, resulting in significant benefits for these businesses and industries.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">According to a recent Forrester Total Economic Impact Study commissioned by Microsoft, it provided a 177 percent return on investment over three years, as well as improvements in employee health and safety, business continuity, customer experience, and customer outcomes.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">Apollo Hospitals has developed an AI-powered Cardiovascular Disease Risk Score API that predicts an individual&#8217;s risk of having a cardiac event within the next seven years. Using the immersive mixed reality experience of the HoloLens 2, this API is combined with an individual&#8217;s health vitals to create a 3D visualization of the person&#8217;s heart&#8217;s current and future states. &#8220;By providing this immersive mixed reality experience and explaining the cause and effect of one&#8217;s lifestyle, the conversation between the doctor and patient has become much more personalized and impactful,&#8221; said Sathya Sriram, CEO of Apollo Hospitals Preventive Health.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/2022/01/20/hands-free-but-precise-is-mixed-reality/">Hands-free but precise is mixed reality.</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic">Daily Topics</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/2022/01/20/hands-free-but-precise-is-mixed-reality/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Asteroid 7482, the size of the Burj Khalifa, will pass Earth on January 18; will it pose any threat?</title>
		<link>https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/2022/01/18/asteroid-7482-the-size-of-the-burj-khalifa-will-pass-earth-on-january-18-will-it-pose-any-threat/</link>
					<comments>https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/2022/01/18/asteroid-7482-the-size-of-the-burj-khalifa-will-pass-earth-on-january-18-will-it-pose-any-threat/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2022 13:37:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[World]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/?p=140</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Jagran Trending Desk, New Delhi: Scientists have discovered that an asteroid the size of the Burj Khalifa will fly past Earth at a distance of 1,230,000 miles today, January 18. The asteroid 7482, also known as 1994 PC1, was named by the National Aeronautics and Space Administration and is about 1.6 km wide. It has [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/2022/01/18/asteroid-7482-the-size-of-the-burj-khalifa-will-pass-earth-on-january-18-will-it-pose-any-threat/">Asteroid 7482, the size of the Burj Khalifa, will pass Earth on January 18; will it pose any threat?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic">Daily Topics</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" width="993" height="495" src="https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/image.png" alt="" class="wp-image-141"/></figure>



<p class="has-medium-font-size"><strong>Jagran Trending Desk, New Delhi:</strong> Scientists have discovered that an asteroid the size of the Burj Khalifa will fly past Earth at a distance of 1,230,000 miles today, January 18. The asteroid 7482, also known as 1994 PC1, was named by the National Aeronautics and Space Administration and is about 1.6 km wide. It has been classified as a &#8220;potentially hazardous object&#8221; due to its proximity to Earth while shooting past.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">According to the space agency, an asteroid is &#8220;potentially hazardous&#8221; if it is 104 meters wide, larger than London&#8217;s Big Ben, and has orbits that bring it within 4.6 million miles of Earth&#8217;s orbit around the Sun.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">Furthermore, it can be a near-Earth object if it is closer than 1.3 au, where 1 au equals 93 million miles.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size"><strong>Will the asteroid 1994 PC1, 7482 cause any harm to the Earth?</strong></p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">Asteroids of this size can cause damage to Earth, but NASA can be confident that 1994 PC1 will safely fly past the planet 1.2 million miles away on January 18.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">NASA posted on Twitter, &#8221; &#8220;Our #PlanetaryDefense experts have been studying the near-Earth #asteroid 1994 PC1 (1 km wide) for decades. Rest assured that 1994 PC1 will safely fly past our planet 1.2 million miles away on Tuesday, January 18.&#8221;</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size"><strong>When will the 1994 PC1 come the closest to Earth?</strong></p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">According to NASA Asteroid Watch, the potentially dangerous asteroid will make its closest approach to Earth on January 18 at 4.51 pm EST (3.21 am IST on January 19). It will be the closest approach for this asteroid for at least the next 200 years, according to astronomers&#8217; calculations.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">On 15 February 2013, an asteroid called the Chelyabinsk meteor — roughly the size of a six-story building — broke up over Chelyabinsk, Russia.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">NASA, the space agency, had previously launched a mission to smash a spacecraft into an asteroid as a test run to prevent a giant space rock from annihilating life on Earth. The Double Asteroid Redirection Test (DART) lifted off from Vandenberg Space Force Base in California at 10:21 p.m. Pacific Time on November 24, 2021, aboard a SpaceX rocket.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">Asteroid 2013 YD48 will pass Earth at a distance of 3,480,000 miles on January 11, 2022. Prior to that, at 47,000 miles per hour, an asteroid nearly three times the size of 2013 YD48 passed within 1.9 million miles of Earth.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/2022/01/18/asteroid-7482-the-size-of-the-burj-khalifa-will-pass-earth-on-january-18-will-it-pose-any-threat/">Asteroid 7482, the size of the Burj Khalifa, will pass Earth on January 18; will it pose any threat?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic">Daily Topics</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/2022/01/18/asteroid-7482-the-size-of-the-burj-khalifa-will-pass-earth-on-january-18-will-it-pose-any-threat/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
