<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>HEALTH &#8211; Daily Topics</title>
	<atom:link href="https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/category/health/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic</link>
	<description>Just another WordPress site</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2022 11:19:48 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/favicon.png</url>
	<title>HEALTH &#8211; Daily Topics</title>
	<link>https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>&#8216;Major barriers&#8217; are broken when pig kidneys implanted in a brain-dead man produce urine for 74 hours.</title>
		<link>https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/2022/01/22/major-barriers-are-broken-when-pig-kidneys-implanted-in-a-brain-dead-man-produce-urine-for-74-hours/</link>
					<comments>https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/2022/01/22/major-barriers-are-broken-when-pig-kidneys-implanted-in-a-brain-dead-man-produce-urine-for-74-hours/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2022 11:19:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[HEALTH]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/?p=274</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Surgeons at the University of Alabama at Birmingham, US, transplanted the kidneys of a genetically engineered pig into a 57-year-old brain-dead man in a scientific first. The kidneys began producing urine within 23 minutes and continued to function for the duration of the experiment, lasting 74 hours. The procedure was described in a scientific paper [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/2022/01/22/major-barriers-are-broken-when-pig-kidneys-implanted-in-a-brain-dead-man-produce-urine-for-74-hours/">&#8216;Major barriers&#8217; are broken when pig kidneys implanted in a brain-dead man produce urine for 74 hours.</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic">Daily Topics</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="has-medium-font-size">Surgeons at the University of Alabama at Birmingham, US, transplanted the kidneys of a genetically engineered pig into a 57-year-old brain-dead man in a scientific first.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">The kidneys began producing urine within 23 minutes and continued to function for the duration of the experiment, lasting 74 hours. The procedure was described in a scientific paper published on January 20 in the American Journal of Transplantation — the first time a pig-to-human transplant procedure had been published in a peer-reviewed journal.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">The study addressed critical safety and feasibility issues in xenotransplantation or transplanting organs from one species into another, and the findings pave the way for future and immediate clinical trials.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">The pig&#8217;s organs had been genetically modified to be more compatible with human bodies and less likely to be rejected. The researchers also discovered no infection in the man caused by pig viruses.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">The kidneys produced urine but were unable to remove creatinine from the blood, as a normal functioning kidney would. The researchers believe this is due to the brain injury suffered by the patient, James Parsons.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">Parsons had been declared dead five days before, and the experiment was called off when other organs began to fail and he began to severely bleed 77 hours into it. At no point were the kidneys rejected.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size"><strong><strong>The investigation</strong></strong></p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">The &#8216;Parsons Model&#8217; is the name given by the surgeons&#8217; team to their pre-clinical model experiment, which will take place in late September 2021.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">The pig&#8217;s genome had ten modifications. Two human genes were inserted to prevent rejection, two for anticoagulation (blood clot prevention), and two for immunomodulatory (immune system regulation).\</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">Three pig carbohydrate antigen genes, as well as the pig growth hormone receptor gene, were deleted. Pigs that have been genetically modified in this way are also compatible with all human blood types because they lack red blood cell antigens.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">Parsons had been declared dead and brain dead for five days prior to the experiment. He had suffered mild-to-moderate kidney damage as well as head trauma. His family agreed to the procedure after exhausting all other transplant options.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">While both transplanted kidneys functioned normally, one produced more urine than the other. Creatinine levels in the body did not decrease, as they normally do in healthy kidneys.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">The researchers do not yet know what is causing either of these changes. They speculate that the surgical procedure may have affected urine production, and the failure to clear creatinine may have resulted from brain cell deterioration.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">According to the researchers, they decided to transplant both kidneys into one patient because the number of pig nephrons (a basic unit of the kidney that produces urine) needed to support a human system was unknown.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size"><strong><strong>The Future of Organ Transplantation</strong></strong></p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">The researchers state in their paper that their trial overcame many barriers to human xenotransplantation trials, while also identifying areas where more research is needed.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">&#8220;Our study suggests that major barriers to human xenotransplantation have been overcome and identifies where new knowledge is required to optimise human xenotransplantation outcomes,&#8221; they write.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">Xenotransplantation research is advancing quickly, and it is viewed as a potential solution to the global organ shortage crisis. Pig organs have recently become more compatible with those of humans, thanks to CRISPR and other genetic editing technologies.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">Pigs are commonly used for xenotransplantation procedures because they are easier to raise and their organs reach adult human size by six months of age.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">At the University of Maryland earlier this year, a genetically modified pig&#8217;s heart was successfully transplanted into a human for the first time. A pig&#8217;s kidney was temporarily externally attached to a patient in New York last year and worked for 54 hours. Pig valves are increasingly being used in the hearts of human patients, and porcine pancreatic tissues have also been grafted onto humans.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/2022/01/22/major-barriers-are-broken-when-pig-kidneys-implanted-in-a-brain-dead-man-produce-urine-for-74-hours/">&#8216;Major barriers&#8217; are broken when pig kidneys implanted in a brain-dead man produce urine for 74 hours.</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic">Daily Topics</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/2022/01/22/major-barriers-are-broken-when-pig-kidneys-implanted-in-a-brain-dead-man-produce-urine-for-74-hours/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Maharashtra reports 48270 new Covid-19 cases, with 52 deaths.</title>
		<link>https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/2022/01/21/maharashtra-reports-48270-new-covid-19-cases-with-52-deaths/</link>
					<comments>https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/2022/01/21/maharashtra-reports-48270-new-covid-19-cases-with-52-deaths/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2022 17:44:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[HEALTH]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/?p=227</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>According to the health department, Maharashtra recorded 48,270 new coronavirus cases on Friday, including 144 Omicron infections and 52 deaths. COVID-19 infections increased by 2,073 from the previous day. A total of 42,391 patients were discharged, bringing the total number of recovered patients to 70,09,823. According to Maharashtra Health Minister Rajesh Tope, despite a high [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/2022/01/21/maharashtra-reports-48270-new-covid-19-cases-with-52-deaths/">Maharashtra reports 48270 new Covid-19 cases, with 52 deaths.</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic">Daily Topics</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="has-medium-font-size">According to the health department, Maharashtra recorded 48,270 new coronavirus cases on Friday, including 144 Omicron infections and 52 deaths.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">COVID-19 infections increased by 2,073 from the previous day.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">A total of 42,391 patients were discharged, bringing the total number of recovered patients to 70,09,823.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">According to Maharashtra Health Minister Rajesh Tope, despite a high positive rate, at least 95% of beds are vacant or hospitalization is lower than in the second wave of COVID-19.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">&#8220;In the state, 95% of the beds are vacant,&#8221; he said. Approximately 4-5% of patients are admitted to hospitals for treatment.&#8221;</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">He went on to say that the state&#8217;s positivity rate is 23.5 percent, but districts like Raigad, Pune, Nashik, and Nanded have a higher positive rate than the state average.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/2022/01/21/maharashtra-reports-48270-new-covid-19-cases-with-52-deaths/">Maharashtra reports 48270 new Covid-19 cases, with 52 deaths.</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic">Daily Topics</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/2022/01/21/maharashtra-reports-48270-new-covid-19-cases-with-52-deaths/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Karnataka: Three babies die after vaccination, according to a report submitted to Chief Minister Basavaraj Bommai.</title>
		<link>https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/2022/01/20/karnataka-three-babies-die-after-vaccination-according-to-a-report-submitted-to-chief-minister-basavaraj-bommai/</link>
					<comments>https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/2022/01/20/karnataka-three-babies-die-after-vaccination-according-to-a-report-submitted-to-chief-minister-basavaraj-bommai/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2022 07:17:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[HEALTH]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/?p=186</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Belagavi District Commissioner MG Hiremath announced on Wednesday (January 19) that he had submitted a preliminary investigation report to Karnataka Chief Minister Basavaraj Bommai in the case of three babies who died after receiving measles-rubella vaccines in the district. &#8220;The discussion is about compensating the families who lost their babies,&#8221; he added. Speaking to the [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/2022/01/20/karnataka-three-babies-die-after-vaccination-according-to-a-report-submitted-to-chief-minister-basavaraj-bommai/">Karnataka: Three babies die after vaccination, according to a report submitted to Chief Minister Basavaraj Bommai.</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic">Daily Topics</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="has-medium-font-size">Belagavi District Commissioner MG Hiremath announced on Wednesday (January 19) that he had submitted a preliminary investigation report to Karnataka Chief Minister Basavaraj Bommai in the case of three babies who died after receiving measles-rubella vaccines in the district. &#8220;The discussion is about compensating the families who lost their babies,&#8221; he added.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">Speaking to the media, he stated that the report, which was submitted by the Belagavi Immunization Monitoring Officer, Eshwar Gadad, had been sent to the Chief Minister.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">According to Hiremath, the report&#8217;s details cannot be made public, and further investigation is underway.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">&#8220;Vials have been sent to both the manufacturing unit and the laboratories. There will be more clarity once they deliver the report. There is no provision for compensation for vaccination-related deaths, but there is one under the Chief Minister&#8217;s Relief Fund that meets certain criteria.&#8221;</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">&#8220;We will recommend compensation to the Joint Secretary,&#8221; he said.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">An initial investigation into the deaths of the three babies has revealed that the nurse who obtained the vaccination vials from the pharmacist on Tuesday had kept them in a hotel fridge with food items, violating all protocols.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">This resulted in bacterial infection, and the three babies died as a result of aseptic shock syndrome after receiving these vaccines. On January 12, two people died after being vaccinated at the Bochagala camp, and one person died on January 11 at the Mallapura camp in Ramdurg taluk.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">At Bochagala, 17 babies were vaccinated, and four babies were vaccinated at Mallapura. Two girls, one 18 months old and the other 12 months old, are being treated in the hospital.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">K. Sudhakar, Karnataka&#8217;s Health Minister, had ordered the suspension of nurse Salma and pharmacist Jayaram.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">According to Eshwar Gadad, the vaccination vials must be taken from the primary health centre (PHC) to vaccination camps and then returned to the PHC.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">&#8220;Nurse Salma should not have transported the vials and stored them in a hotel refrigerator. All of the vials she obtained have been returned and tested. This is a regrettable occurrence. The health department has taken care of it, and parents can come forward to have their babies vaccinated &#8220;He continued.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">Pavithra Halagur, a 13-month-old baby girl, died the same day after receiving the first dose of the vaccine, after experiencing nausea and vomiting a few hours later.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">Umesh Karagundi, a 14-month-old child, was admitted to Belagavi Institute of Medical Sciences but died on January 15 due to convulsions in the intensive care unit.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">Chetana, a 15-month-old baby who received the vaccine jab in the Mallapura camp, died on January 15.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size">Children under the age of 15 months receive the first dose of measles-rubella vaccine, and those over the age of 15 months receive a second dose.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/2022/01/20/karnataka-three-babies-die-after-vaccination-according-to-a-report-submitted-to-chief-minister-basavaraj-bommai/">Karnataka: Three babies die after vaccination, according to a report submitted to Chief Minister Basavaraj Bommai.</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic">Daily Topics</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/2022/01/20/karnataka-three-babies-die-after-vaccination-according-to-a-report-submitted-to-chief-minister-basavaraj-bommai/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Go For Western Economy With These Pioneering</title>
		<link>https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/2020/01/12/go-for-western-economy-with-these-pioneering/</link>
					<comments>https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/2020/01/12/go-for-western-economy-with-these-pioneering/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2020 16:35:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[HEALTH]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://demo.themeansar.com/newsup/lite/?p=40</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>but it is too much for my strength &#8212; I sink under the weight of the splendour of these visions! I am alone, and feel the charm of existence in this spot, which was created for the bliss of souls like mine. I am so happy, my dear friend, so absorbed in the exquisite sense [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/2020/01/12/go-for-western-economy-with-these-pioneering/">Go For Western Economy With These Pioneering</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic">Daily Topics</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p> but it is too much for my strength &#8212; I sink under the weight of the  splendour of these visions! </p>



<p>I am alone, and feel the charm of existence in this spot, which was created for the bliss of souls like mine. I am so happy, my dear friend, so absorbed in the exquisite sense of mere tranquil existence, that I neglect my talents.</p>



<span id="more-40"></span>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p> I should be incapable of drawing a single stroke at the present moment;  and yet I feel that I never was a greater artist than now. </p></blockquote>



<p>When, while the lovely valley teems with vapour around me, and the meridian sun strikes the upper surface of the impenetrable foliage of my trees, and but a few stray gleams steal into the inner sanctuary, I throw myself down among the tall grass by the trickling stream; and, as I lie close to the earth, a thousand unknown plants are noticed by me: when I hear the buzz of the little world among the stalks, and grow familiar with the countless indescribable forms of the insects and flies, then I feel the presence of the Almighty, who formed us in his own image, and the breath of that universal love which bears and sustains us, as it floats around us in an eternity of bliss; and then, my friend, when darkness overspreads my eyes, and heaven and earth seem to dwell in my soul and absorb its power, like the form of a beloved mistress, then I often think with longing, Oh, would I could describe these conceptions, could impress upon paper all that is living so full and warm within me, that it might be the mirror of my soul, as my soul is the mirror of the infinite God!</p>



<p>I am so happy, my dear friend, so absorbed in the exquisite sense of mere tranquil existence, that I neglect my talents. I should be incapable of drawing a single stroke at the present moment; and yet I feel that I never was a greater artist than now. When, while the lovely valley teems with vapour around me, and the meridian sun strikes the upper surface of the impenetrable foliage of my trees, and but a few stray gleams steal into the inner sanctuary, I throw myself down among the tall grass by the trickling stream; and, as I lie close to the earth, a thousand unknown plants are noticed by me: when I hear the buzz of the little world among the stalks, and grow familiar with the countless indescribable forms of the insects and</p>



<p></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/2020/01/12/go-for-western-economy-with-these-pioneering/">Go For Western Economy With These Pioneering</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic">Daily Topics</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://jacob2705.github.io/DailyTopic/2020/01/12/go-for-western-economy-with-these-pioneering/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
